Data Engineer with 4+ years of experience in building and maintaing data pipelines and models on Big data. Possesses strong analytical skills, excellent problem-solving abilities, and a deep understanding of database technologies and systems. Skilled in python and Cloud platform operations.

Work History

2022-02 - present

Data Design Executive

YouGov, London

- Increased product team efficiency through automating manual tasks through creation and maintenance of API operations
- Created automated web scraping process to increase efficiency of data extraction by 70% through coding and unique selenium operation
- Maintenance of several sustainable automation processes for data extraction, wrangling investigative analysis and report creation
- Developed a Python and SQL code-based project to extract, transform and present data in Power BI dashboard from Snowflake for stakeholders
- Appropriate testing and monitoring to ensure right data engineering practices and data quality
- Creative sessions with team members to develop ideas into effective new features and processes for effective data collection
- Collaborations with global stakeholders to achieve strategic goals of the company.

2021-10

Data Analyst

- 2021-11

Watt renewables, Lagos

- Saved 100 % of the company's expenditure on data visualization tool without compromising data integrity
- Collaborated on ETL (Extract, Transform, Load) tasks, maintaining data integrity and verifying pipeline stability.
- · Designed data models for complex analysis needs.

2020-07

- 2021-07

Data Analyst

Vesicash, Lagos

- Identified, analyzed and interpreted trends or patterns in complex data sets
- Synthesized complex analytics-derived insights into easy-to-understand, actionable recommendations for business users.
- Developed customized reports, summarizing and presenting data in a visually appealing format.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to identify business needs and data sources.

Education

2010-01

Electrical/Electronics Engineering, Bachelor of Science

- 2015-12

Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife

Certificates

2019-09 Introduction to Programming using Python

2021-12 AWS certified Cloud Practitioner

2023-01 dbt Fundamentals

Olutade Ogundele

Data Engineer

Personal Info

Email

tadeogundele@gmail.com

Phone

07887493120

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/olutadeogundele/

Website

https://oluwatobij4.github.io/

Skills

Database Design

Data warehousing and Analytics

ETL/ELT process development

Machine learning

Effective communication skills

Technical Writing

Software

Snowflake

Amazon Redshift

Apache Kafka

Apache Spark

Airflow

Power BI

Git

Terraform

DBT

Microsoft Excel

Languages

Python, Pandas

SQL

jinja